Toplam (294 adet) örnek.
====================
T.R.Kuphaldt kitaplarının ücretsiz indirilebileceği site: www.allaboutcircuits.com
LTspice-XVII simülatörünün ücretsiz indirilebileceği site: www.analog.com

1. DC: Direct Current (67 adet)
--------------------------------------------------------------
    1.1. Basic Concepts of Electricity
        1.1.1. Static electricity
        1.1.2. Conductors, insulators and electron flow
        1.1.3. Electric circuits
        1.1.4. Voltage and current
        1.1.5. Resistance
        1.1.6. Voltage and current in a practical circuit
        1.1.7. Conventional versus electron flow
    1.2. Ohm's Law
        1.2.1. How voltage, current and resistance relate
            d10201a.asc: Pilli elektron çekim kaynaklı gerilim, lamba direnci ve akım örneği.
            d10201b.asc: Pilli elektron çekim kaynaklı gerilim, lamba direnci ve akım örneği.
            d10201c.asc: Pilli elektron çekim kaynaklı gerilim, lamba direnci ve akım örneği.
        1.2.2. An analogy of ohm's law
        1.2.3. Power in electric circuits
        1.2.4. Calculating electric power
            d10204a.asc: Verili gerilim ve direnç değerleriyle gücün hesapanması örneği.
            d10204b.asc: Verili gerilim ve direnç değerleriyle gücün hesapanması örneği.
        1.2.5. Resistors
            d10205.asc: Verili gerilim ve akım değerleriyle devredeki direncin ve onun güç sarfiyatının hesapanması örneği.
        1.2.6. Nonlinear conduction
        1.2.7. Circuit wiring
        1.2.8. Polarity of voltage drops
        1.2.9. Computer simulation of electric circuits
            d10209a.asc: LTspice-XVII op analiziyle devrenin akım, gerilim ve güç değerleri örneği.
            d10209b.asc: Gerilim 3 kat artınca, direnç güç sarfiyatının 9 kat artması LTspice .op örneği.
            d10209c.asc: LTspice dc sweep/süpürme ile akımXvoltaj grafiği örneği.
    1.3. Electrical Safety
        1.3.1. The importance of electrical safety
        1.3.2. Physiological effects of electricity
        1.3.3. Shock current path
        1.3.4. Ohm's law (again)
        1.3.5. Safe practices
        1.3.6. Emergency response
        1.3.7. Comman sources of hazard
        1.3.8. Safe circuit design
        1.3.9. Safe meter usage
        1.3.10. Electrical shock data
    1.4. Scientific Notation and Metrix Prefix
        1.4.1. Scientific notation
            d10401a.asc: LTspice programında kullanılan bilimsel gösterim örneği.
            d10401b.asc: Artıralan direnç değeriyle LTspice programında kullanılan bilimsel gösterim örneği.
        1.4.2. Arithmetic with scientific notation
        1.4.3. Metric notation
        1.4.4. Metric prefix conversions
        1.4.5. Hand calculator use
        1.4.6. Scientific notation in SPICE
    1.5. Series and Parallel Circuits
        1.5.1. What are "series" and "parallel" circuits?
        1.5.2. Simple series circuits
            d10502.asc: 3 adet basit seri dirençli devredeki akım, gerilim düşüşü ve güç sarfiyatı değerleri örneği.
        1.5.3. Simple parallel circuits
            d10503.asc: 3 paralel dirençli devrede gerilim, akım ve güç değerleri örneği.
        1.5.4. Conductance
        1.5.5. Power calculations
        1.5.6. Correct use of Ohm's Law
        1.5.7. Component failure analysis
        1.5.8. Building simple resistor cicuits
    1.6. Divider Circuits and Kirchhooff's Laws
        1.6.1. Voltage divider circuits
            d10601a.asc: Bir sıralı devrede herbir dirençteki gerilim düşüşü örneği.
            d10601b.asc: Gerilimi 4 kat artan sıralı devremizde herbir dirençteki gerilim düşüşü örneği.
        1.6.2. Kirchhoff's Voltage Law (KVL)
        1.6.3. Current divider circuits
            d10603a.asc: Koşut 3 direncin DA gerilimli devrede akım bölücü olarak kullanılması örneği.
            d10603b.asc: Gerilimi 4 misli artırılan önceki koşut 3 direncin DA gerilimli devrede akım bölücü olarak kullanılması örneği.
        1.6.4. Kirchhoff's Current Law (KCL)
    1.7. Series-Parallel Combination Circuits
        1.7.1. What is a series-parallel circuit?
        1.7.2. Analysis tecnique
            d10702.asc: Sıralı ve koşut dirençli devredeki gerilim, akım ve güç sarfiyatları analizi örneği.
        1.7.3. Re-drawing complex schematics
            d10703a.asc: Karmaşık bükümlü devrelerin sadeleştirilmesi örneği.
            d10703b.asc: Bükümlü karmaşık 7 dirençli devrenin sadeleştirilip analizi örneği.
        1.7.4. Component failure analysis
        1.7.5. Building series-parallel resistor circuits
            d10705a.asc: Sıralı-koşut direnç devresinin delikli breadboard/ekmekpanosu'na kurulması örneği.
            d10705b.asc: Karışık koşut-sıralı devrenin vidalı terminalstrip/bar/terminal-çubuğuna kurulması örneği.
    1.8. DC Metering Circuits
        1.8.1. What's a meter?
        1.8.2. Voltage design
            d10802a.asc: Tam ekran sapması 1 mA olan ve azami 0.5 V gerilimi ölçen voltmetre/gerilimölçer örneği.
            d10802b.asc: 1mA 500Ohm akımölçerle 10V azami gerilimi tamekran sapmasıyla ölçme örneği.
            d10802c.asc: 1mA akımölçerin, 5 seçici düğmeli sıralı çarpan dirençle 1000-100-10-1 V gerilim ölçmesi örneği.
            d10802d.asc: 1mA akımölçerle seçenekli düğmeli 1000-100-10-1V gerilimi temin edilebilir sıralı çarpan dirençle ölçme örneği.
        1.8.3. Voltmeter impact on measured circuit
            d10803a.asc: Ölçülen direnç bölücü devrede gerilimölçerin hatalı etkisi örneği.
            d10803b.asc: Sıfır akım dönüştüreç kontrollu yüklemesiz gerilim ölçer devresi örneği.
        1.8.4. Ammeter design
            d10804a.asc: Çoklu şant/yankol dirençli ammetre/akımölçer devresi örneği.
            d10804b.asc: Sık akım ölçümlerinde 1 Ohm yankol dirençli pratik gerilimölçerin kullanılması örneği.
        1.8.5. Ammeter impact on measured circuit
            d10805a.asc: Düşük 2 koşut dirençli bir DA devresindeki akım değerleri örneği.
            d10805b.asc: Düşük 2 koşut dirençli bir DA devresinde akımölçerin abartılı etkisi örneği.
            d10805c.asc: Düşük 2 koşut dirençli bir DA devresinde akımölçerin abartılı etkisi örneği.
        1.8.6. Ohmmeter design
            d10806.asc: Bir analog/örneksel Ohmmetre/dirençölçer ibresinin 4 çeyrek dirençlerinin hesabı örneği.
        1.8.7. High voltage ohmmeters
        1.8.8. Multimeters
        1.8.9. Kelvin (4-wire) resistance measurement
        1.8.10. Bridge circuits
        1.8.11. Wattmeter design
        1.8.12. Creating custom calibration resistance
    1.9. Electrical Instrumentation Signals
        1.9.1. Analog and digital signals
        1.9.2. Voltage signal systems
        1.9.3. Current signal systems
        1.9.4. Tachogenerators
        1.9.5. Thermocouples
        1.9.6. pH measurement
        1.9.7. Strain gauges
    1.10. DC Network Analysis
        1.10.1. What's network analysis?
        1.10.2. Branch current method
            d11002.asc: KCL/Kirchhoff'sCurrentLaw/KirçhofAkımKanunu ile branch/dallanan akım metodu örneği.
        1.10.3. Mesh current method
            1.10.3.1. Mesh current by conventional method
                d11003a.asc: KVL/Kirchhoff'sVoltageLaw/KirçhofGerilimKanunu ile mesh/dolanan akım metodu örneği.
                d11003b.asc: KVL ile dolanan 3 mesh/hücre gözlü akım denklemi çözümü örneği.
                d11003c.asc: Wheatstone köprü dengesiz devresinde dolanan akım örneği.
            1.10.3.2. Mesh current by inspection
                d11003d.asc: KVL ile dolanan 3 mesh/hücre gözlü akım denklemlerinin kutupsuz direnç çözümü örneği.
        1.10.4. Node voltage method
            d11004a.asc: Node/boğum gerilimi yöntemiyle V3 ve V4 gerilimlerini hesaplama örneği.
            d11004b.asc: Dallanan boğum akım denklemleriyle V1, V2, V3 boğum gerilimlerini hesaplama örneği.
        1.10.5. Introduction to network theorems
        1.10.6. Millman's Theorem
            d11006.asc: Millman'ın dallanan direnç-batarya gerilimi teoremi örneği.
        1.10.7. Superposition Theorem
            d11007.asc: Super(im)pose/üst-üsteleme teoremiyle çoklu gerilim/akım kaynaklarının tikel etkilerini ekleme örneği.
        1.10.8. Thevenin's Theorem
            d11008.asc: Thevenin teoremiyle doğrusal her devreyi seri gerilim kaynağı ve dirence indirgeme örneği.
        1.10.9. Norton's Theorem
            d11009.asc: Norton teoremiyle doğrusal her devreyi koşut akım kaynağı ve dirence indirgeme örneği.
        1.10.10Thevenin-Norton equivalencies
            d11010a.asc: 3 dirençli devrede herbir direncin gerilim bölücü olarak kullanılması örneği.
            d11010b.asc: Akım kaynaklı devredeki koşut dirençlerin akım bölücü olarak kullanılması örneği.
            d11010c.asc: Verilen devrenin Ryük dirençten görülen Vth-Rth ve Inor-Rnor eşdeğeri örneği.
            d11010d.asc: Gerilim ve akım kaynaklı dirençler devresinin Thevenin ve Norton eşdeğeri örneği.
            d11010e.asc: Bağımlı R2 dirençli devrenin Thevenin ve Norton eşdeğerleri örneği.
            d11010f.asc: Güç kaynaksız bağımlı dirençli devrenin Rth hesaplanması örneği.
        1.10.11. Millman's Theorem revisited
            d11011.asc: Doğrusal her devreyi Thevenin veya Norton eşdeğer Ryük devresine çevirme örneği.
        1.10.12. Maximum Power Transfer Theorem
            d11012a.asc: Ryük ve Rth eşitliğinin yük direncine azami güç aktarımı sağlaması örneği.
            d11012b.asc: Ryük < Rth düşüklüğünün yük direncine daha az güç aktarımı sağlaması örneği.
            d11012c.asc: Ryük > Rth yüksekliğinin yük direncine daha az güç aktarımı sağlaması örneği.
        1.10.13. Delta-Y and Y-D conversions
            d11013a.asc: Dengesiz köprü devresinin üst Delta/Y çevrimiyle analizi örneği.
            d11013b.asc: Dengesiz köprü devresinin alt Delta/Y çevrimiyle analizi örneği.
    1.11. Batteries and Power Systems
        1.11.1. Electron activity in chemical reactions
        1.11.2. Battery construction
        1.11.3. Battery ratings
            d11103a.asc: Tam dolu araba bataryasının yüksüz ve yüklü gerilim değeri örneği.
            d11103b.asc: Hafif dejarjlı araba bataryasının yüksüz ve yüklü gerilim değeri örneği.
            d11103c.asc: Orta dejarjlı araba bataryasının yüksüz ve yüklü gerilim değeri örneği.
            d11103d.asc: Ölgün dejarjlı araba bataryasının yüksüz ve yüklü gerilim değeri örneği.
        1.11.4. Special-purpose batteries
        1.11.5. Practical considerations
    1.12. Physics of Conductors and Insulators
        1.12.1. Introduction
        1.12.2. Conductor size
        1.12.3. Conductor ampacity
        1.12.4. Fuses
        1.12.5. Specific resistance
            d11205.asc: Uzun hatlarda istenen yük gerilimi için tel kalınlığı hesabı örneği.
        1.12.6. Temperature coefficient of resistance
            d11206a.asc: Direnç değerlerinin ısı katsayısı doğrultusunda değişmesi örneği.
            d11206b.asc: Direnç değerlerinin ısı katsayısı doğrultusunda değişmesi örneği.
        1.12.7. Superconductivity
        1.12.8. Insulator breakdown voltage
        1.12.9. Data
    1.13. Capacitors
        1.13.1. Electric fields and capacitance
        1.13.2. Capacitors and calculus
        1.13.3. Factors affecting capacitance
        1.13.4. Series and parallel capacitors
        1.13.5. Practical considerations
    1.14. Magnetism and Electromagnetism
        1.14.1. Permanent magnets
        1.14.2. Electromagnetism
        1.14.3. Magnetic units of measurement
        1.14.4. Permeability and saturation
        1.14.5. Electromagnetic induction
        1.14.6. Mutual inductance
    1.15. Inductors
        1.15.1. Magnetic fields and inductance
        1.15.2. Inductors and calculus
        1.15.3. Factors affecting inductance
        1.15.4. Series and parallel inductors
        1.15.5. Practical considerations
    1.16. RC and L/R Time Constants
        1.16.1. Electrical transients
        1.16.2. Capacitor transient response
            d11602.asc: Doğru akımda sığaçların geçici şarj sürecinin analizi örneği.
        1.16.3. Inductor transient response
            d11603.asc: Doğru akımda irkileçlerin geçici şarj sürecinin analizi örneği.
        1.16.4. Voltage and current calculations
        1.16.5. Why L/R and not LR?
        1.16.6. Complex voltage and current calculations
        1.16.7. Complex circuits
            d11607.asc: Sıralı-koşut dirençli karmaşık sığaç devresinde T örneği
        1.16.8. Solving for unknown time

2. AC Alternating Current (80 adet)
-------------------------------------------------
    2.1. Basic AC Theory
        2.1.1 What is alternating current (AC)?
        2.1.2 AC waveforms
        2.1.3 Measurements of AC magnitude
        2.1.4 Simple AC circuit calculations
            d20104.asc: Basit dirençli AA-AlternatifAkım devre hesapları örneği.
        2.1.5 AC phase
        2.1.6 Principles of radio
    2.2. Complex Numbers
        2.2.1 Introduction
        2.2.2 Vectors and AC waveforms
        2.2.3 Simple vector addition
        2.2.4 Complex vector addition
        2.2.5 Polar and rectangular notation
        2.2.6 Complex number arithmetic
        2.2.7 More on AC ”polarity”
        2.2.8 Some examples with AC circuits
            d20208a.asc: Faz açıları farklı iki AA gerilim kaynağı örneği.
            d20208b.asc: Faz açıları farklı üç AA gerilim kaynağı örneği.
            d20208c.asc: Faz açıları farklı üç AA-AlternatifAkım gerilim kaynağı örneği.
    2.3. Reactance and Impedance - Inductive
        2.3.1 AC resistor circuits
        2.3.2 AC inductor circuits
        2.3.3 Series resistor-inductor circuits
            d20303.asc: Sıralı direnç ve irkileç devresi örneği.
        2.3.4 Parallel resistor-inductor circuits
            d20304.asc: Koşut direnç-irkileç devresi örneği.
        2.3.5 Inductor quirks
        2.3.6 More on the “skin effect”
    2.4. Reactance and Impedance - Capacitive
        2.4.1 AC resistor circuits
        2.4.2 AC capacitor circuits
        2.4.3 Series resistor-capacitor circuits
            d20403.asc: Sıralı direnç ve sığaç devresi örneği.
        2.4.4 Parallel resistor-capacitor circuits
            d20404.asc: Koşut direnç ve sığaç devresi örneği.
        2.4.5 Capacitor quirks .
    2.5. Reactance and Impedance - R, L and C
        2.5.1 Review of R, X, and Z
        2.5.2 Series R, L, and C
           d20502.asc: Sıralı direnç, irkileç ve sığaç devresi örneği.
        2.5.3 Parallel R, L, and C
            d20503.asc: Koşut direnç, irkileç ve sığaç devresi örneği.
        2.5.4 Series-parallel R, L, and C
            d20504.asc: Sıralı-koşut RLC devresi örneği.
        2.5.5 Susceptance and Admittance
    2.6. Resonance
        2.6.1 An electric pendulum
        2.6.2 Simple parallel (tank circuit) resonance
            d20602.asc: Basit koşut sığaç ve irkileç tank rezonans/çınlanım devresi örneği.
        2.6.3 Simple series resonance
            d20603.asc: Basit sıralı sığaç irkileç çınlanım devresi örneği.
        2.6.4 Applications of resonance
        2.6.5 Resonance in series-parallel circuits
            d20605a.asc: Koşut LC'de sıralı RL çınlanım devresi örneği.
            d20605b.asc: Koşut LC'de sıralı RC çınlanım devresi örneği.
            d20605c.asc: Sıralı LC'de koşut RL çınlanım devresi örneği.
            d20605d.asc: Sıralı LC'de koşut RC çınlanım devresi örneği.
            d20605e.asc: Sıralı RLC'de  çınlanım sıklığı seçiciliğinin genişlemesi örneği.
        2.6.6 Q and bandwidth of a resonant circuit
            d20606a.asc: Sıralı çınlanım devresinde bantgenişliği ve kalite faktörü örneği.
            d20606b.asc: Koşut LC tank devresinde sıralı RL BG ve Q örneği.
    2.7. Mixed-Frequency AC Signals
        2.7.1 Introduction
        2.7.2 Square wave signals
            d20702a.asc: Karedalga sinyalin tikel sinüs harmoniklerinin karışımından oluşması örneği.
            d20702b.asc: Karedalga sinyalin içerdiği sinüs dalgası harmoniklerine Fourier dönüşümü örneği.
        2.7.3 Other waveshapes
            d20703a.asc: Çiftüşekle yarım-dalga doğrultucu dalgabiçimi örneği.
            d20703b.asc: 4 köprü çiftüşekle tam-dalga doğrultucu dalgabiçimi örneği.
        2.7.4 More on spectrum analysis
        2.7.5 Circuit effects
            d20705.asc: Farklı frekanslı gerilim kaynaklarının devre etkileri örneği.
    2.8. Filters
        2.8.1 What is a filter?
        2.8.2 Low-pass filters
            d20802a.asc: Sıralı irkileçle düşük-geçiş süzgeci örneği.
            d20802b.asc: Koşut sığaçla düşük-geçiş süzgeci örneği.
        2.8.3 High-pass filters
            d20803a.asc: Sıralı sığaçla yüksek-geçiş süzgeci örneği.
            d20803b.asc: Koşut irkileçle yüksek-geçiş süzgeci örneği.
        2.8.4 Band-pass filters
            d20804a.asc: Sığaçlı bant-geçiş süzgeç devresi örneği.
            d20804b.asc: İrkileçli bant-geçiş süzgeç devresi örneği.
        2.8.5 Band-stop filters
            d20805.asc: "İkiz-T" bant-yasak süzgeç devresi örneği.
        2.8.6 Resonant filters
            d20806a.asc: Seri irkileç ve sığaç rezonans devreli bant-geçiş süzgeci örneği.
            d20806b.asc: Koşut LC devreli bant-geçiş çınlanım örneği.
            d20806c.asc: Yük direncine koşut sıralı LC bant-yasak süzgeci örneği.
            d20806d.asc: Koşut tank LC sıralı Ryük bant-yasak süzgeç örneği.
            d20806e.asc: Sığaçlı irkileçle düşük-bant geçiş süzgeç örneği.
            d20806f.asc: Giriş-çıkış empedansı eşitlenen düşük-bant geçiş LC süzgeç örneği.
            d20806g.asc: ACdalgalı gerilimden DC dalgasıza ilerleme örneği.
    2.9. Transformers
        2.9.1 Mutual inductance and basic operation
            d20901a.asc: Karşılıklı irkileçli dönüştürücü devre örneği.
            d20901b.asc: Daha düşük yük direnciyle karşılıklı irkileçli dönüştürücü devre örneği.
            d20901c.asc: Ryük 15 Ohm düşük dirençle karşılıklı irkileçli dönüştürücü devre örneği.
            d20901d.asc: K=1 ideal eşleşmeli karşılıklı irkileçli dönüştürücü devre örneği.
            d20901e.asc: k=1 ve L1=L2=1H karşılıklı irkileçli dönüştürücü devre örneği.
            d20901f.asc: k=1, Ryük=1K ve L1=L2=1H karşılıklı irkileçli dönüştürücü devre örneği.
            d20901g.asc: k=1, Ryük=1K ve L1=L2=100H karşılıklı irkileçli dönüştürücü devre örneği.
        2.9.2 Step-up and step-down transformers
            d20902.asc: Düşüren 10:1 dönüştüreç devresi örneği.
        2.9.3 Electrical isolation
            d20903.asc: Elektriksel yalıtımlı düşüren 10:1 dönüştüreç devresi örneği.
        2.9.4 Phasing
            d20904.asc: Dönüştüreç giriş çıkışlarının aynı ve farklı (180 derece) fazda olması örneği.
        2.9.5 Winding configurations
        2.9.6 Voltage regulation
            d20906.asc: Yüksek ve düşük yükler altındaki dönüştüreç gerilim düzeltmesi örneği
        2.9.7 Special transformers and applications
            d209071a.asc: Tam yük verimi için uygun empedans dönüşüm oranı örneği.
            d209071b.asc: Dönüştürecin primer ve segonder empedans uyumu örneği.
            d209073.asc: HV hatlarında dönüştüreçli gerilim ve akım ölçme örneği.
        2.9.8 Practical considerations
    2.10. Polyphase AC Circuits
        2.10.1 Single-phase power systems
            d21001a.asc: Tek fazlı güç sistemlerinde düşük gerilim veya ekonomik kablo dengesi örneği.
            d21001b.asc: Aynı güçte iki sıralı yükle gerilim-ekonomi dengesi örneği.
        2.10.2 Three-phase power systems
            d21002a.asc: Tek fazdan 3-fazlı dağıtım şebekesine geçiş örneği.
            d21002b.asc: 3-fazlı 220 KV hattan 120 V'a trafo dağıtım örneği.
        2.10.3 Phase rotation
        2.10.4 Polyphase motor design
        2.10.5 Three-phase Y and Delta configurations
            d21005a.asc: 3-fazlı Y-Yıldız ve D-Delta bağlantıları örneği.
            d21005b.asc: 3-fazlı dönüştüreç Y-Y-Y bağlantıları örneği.
            d21005c.asc: 3-fazlı Y-Delta-Y bağlantılı dönüştüreç örneği.
            d21005d.asc: 3-fazlı D-Y-D bağlantılı dönüştüreç örneği.
        2.10.6 Three-phase transformer circuits
            d21006a.asc: 3-fazlı Y-Y dönüştüreç bağlantısı giriş-çıkışları örneği.
            d21006b.asc: 3-fazlı Y-D bağlantılı trafonun giriş-çıkışı örneği.
            d21006c.asc: 3-fazlı dönüştürecin D-Y bağlantılı giriş-çıkış örneği.
            d21006d.asc: 3-fazlı trafonun D-D bağlantılı giriş-çıkışları örneği.
        2.10.7 Harmonics in polyphase power systems
            d21007a.asc: Tek fazlı sinüs gerilimin kaynaklı yük harmonikleri örneği.
            d21007b.asc: Yüke koşut farklı frekanlı akım kaynağının harmonik etkisi örneği.
            d21007c.asc: Yüke koşut 4  farklı frekanslı akım kaynağının harmonik etkisi örneği.
            d21007d.asc: 3-fazlı Y-Y kaynak/yükle koşut akım kaynaklarının harmonikleri örneği.
            d21007e.asc: 3-fazlı D-Y dağıtım hattında yüke koşut akım kaynakları harmonikleri örneği.
            d21007f.asc: 3-fazlı D-D dağıtım hattında yüke koşut akım kaynakları harmonikleri örneği.
        2.10.8 Harmonic phase sequences
    2.11. Power Factor
        2.11.1 Power in resistive and reactive AC circuits
            d21101.asc: AA dirençsel ve tepkisel devrelerdeki güç örneği.
        2.11.2 True, Reactive, and Apparent power
        2.11.3 Calculating power factor
            d21103.asc: Güç faktörünü artırmak için irkileçe koşut sığaç bağlantısı örneği.
        2.11.4 Practical power factor correction
            d21104.asc: Pratik bir güç faktörü düzeltme örneği.
    2.12. AC Metering Circuits
        2.12.1 AC voltmeters and ammeters
        2.12.2 Frequency and phase measurement
        2.12.3 Power measurement
        2.12.4 Power quality measurement
        2.12.5 AC bridge circuits
        2.12.6 AC instrumentation transducers
    2.13. AC Motors
        2.13.1 Introduction
        2.13.2 Synchronous Motors
        2.13.3 Synchronous condenser
        2.13.4 Reluctance motor
        2.13.5 Stepper motors
        2.13.6 Brushless DC motor
        2.13.7 Tesla polyphase induction motors
        2.13.8 Wound rotor induction motors
        2.13.9 Single-phase induction motors
        2.13.10 Other specialized motors
        2.13.11 Selsyn (synchro) motors
        2.13.12 AC commutator motors
    2.14. Transmission Lines
        2.14.1 A 50-ohm cable?
        2.14.2 Circuits and the speed of light
        2.14.3 Characteristic impedance
        2.14.4 Finite-length transmission lines
        2.14.5 “Long” and “short” transmission lines
        2.14.6 Standing waves and resonance
            d21406a.asc: Nakil hatlarında duran dalgalar ve rezonans örneği.
            d21406b.asc: Yük direnci açık devre iken nakil hattı sinyalleri örneği.
            d21406c.asc: Yük direnci kısadevre iken nakil hattı sinyalleri örneği.
            d21406d.asc: Yük direncinin karakteristikten farklı/büyük olması örneği.
        2.14.7 Impedance transformation
            d21407a.asc: Nakil hatlarındaki empedans dönüşümü örneği.
            d21407b.asc: Sabit frekanslı nakil hatlarındaki farklı kaynak yük empedans eşleştirme örneği
            d21407c.asc: Sabit frekanslı nakil hatlarındaki farklı kaynak yük empedans eşleştirme örneği
        2.14.8 Waveguides

3. Semiconductors (147 adet)
-------------------------------------------
    3.1. Amplifiers and Active Devices
        3.1.1 From electric to electronic
            d30301.asc: Basit bir çiftüşek devresi örneği.
        3.1.2 Active versus passive devices
        3.1.3 Amplifiers
        3.1.4 Amplifier gain
        3.1.5 Decibels
        3.1.6 Absolute dB scales
        3.1.7 Attenuators
            d301072.asc: T-kısım zayıflatıcı direnç değerlerinin hesaplanması örneği.
            d301073.asc: PI-kısım zayıflatıcı direnç değerlerinin hesaplanması örneği.
            d301074.asc: L-kısım zayıflatıcı direnç değerlerinin hesaplanması örneği.
            d301075.asc: Köprülü-T kısım zayıflatıcı direnç değerlerinin hesaplanması örneği.
    3.2. Solid-State Device Theory
        3.2.1 Introduction
        3.2.2 Quantum physics
        3.2.3 Valence and Crystal structure
        3.2.4 Band theory of solids
        3.2.5 Electrons and “holes”
        3.2.6 The P-N junction
        3.2.7 Junction diodes
        3.2.8 Bipolar junction transistors
        3.2.9 Junction field-effect transistors
        3.2.10 Insulated-gate field-effect transistors (MOSFET)
        3.2.11 Thyristors
        3.2.12 Semiconductor manufacturing techniques
        3.2.13 Superconducting devices
        3.2.14 Quantum devices
        3.2.15 Semiconductor devices in SPICE
    3.3. Diodes and Rectifiers
        3.3.1 Introduction
        3.3.2 Meter check of a diode
            d30302.asc: Bir çiftüşeğin düz-ters kutup ölçümü örneği.
        3.3.3 Diode ratings
        3.3.4 Rectifier circuits
            d30304a.asc: Yarım dalga doğrultaç devresi örneği.
            d30304b.asc: Tam dalga orta çıkış dönüştüreç ve çiftüşek devresi örneği.
            d30304c.asc: Orta bağlantı dönüştüreçli düal kutuplu tam dalga doğrutaç devresi örneği.
            d30304d.asc: Tam dalga köprü doğrultaç düz şema devre örneği.
            d30304e.asc: 3 Y-fazlı tam-dalga köprü doğrultaç devresi örneği.
            d30304f.asc: 6-faz 12-diyot -tepeli tam dalga doğrultaç devre örneği.
            d30304g.asc: Giriş 3-faz Y, çıkış 3-faz Y ve D, 12 tepeli doğrultaç örneği.
        3.3.5 Peak detector
            d30305.asc: Sığaç ve çiftüşekle çıktıda sin tepe gerilim değerine sabitlenme örneği.
        3.3.6 Clipper circuits
            d30306a.asc: Çıktıda ters tek çiftüşekle negatif dalgaların kırpılması örneği.
            d30306b.asc: Çıktıda düal zıt çiftüşekle dalganın +/- çiftüşek düzkutup eşiğinde kırpılması örneği.
            d30306c.asc: Düal zıt çifüşeklerin kısadevre eşik gerilimlerini artıran kırpılma örneği.
        3.3.7 Clamper circuits
            d30307a.asc: Seri sığaç ve çiftüşekle çıktı sinyalin aşağı kaydırılması örneği.
            d30307b.asc: Seri sığaç ve çiftüşekle çıktı sinyalin yukarı kaydırılması örneği.
            d30307c.asc: Ters gerilimli sığaçlı çiftüşeğe pozitif kaydırıcı dc kaynak ilavesi örneği.
        3.3.8 Voltage multipliers
            d30308a.asc: Kenetleyici ve zirveci devreli yarım dalga gerilim duble çarpanı örneği.
            d30308b.asc: Tam dalga çift zirveciyle duble gerilim çarpanı örneği.
            d30308c.asc: Zıt iki diyotlu tamdalga ve kenetleyiciyle üç-katlı gerilim çıktısı örneği.
            d30308d.asc: İki kenetleyici ve iki zirveciyle dört katlı çıktı gerilimi örneği.
            d30308e.asc: Cockcroft-Walton sekiz çarpanlı gerilim çıktısı örneği.
        3.3.9 Inductor commutating circuits
            d30309s.asc: İrkileç geritepi kıvılcımını hafifletici çiftüşek devresi örneği.
            d30309b.asc: Akım kontrollu düğme "csw" açıkken kapanması örneği.
            d30309c.asc: Akım kontrollu düğme "csw" kapalıyken açılması örneği.
            d30309d.asc: Akım kontrollu düğme "csw" ile irkileç geritepi testi örneği.
            d30309e.asc: Düğme kontrollü irkileç geritepi deşarjı örneği.
            d30309f.asc: Basit akım düğmesi kontrollü irkileç geritepi deşarjı örneği.
        3.3.10 Diode switching circuits
            d303101.asc: Çiftüşekle AND ve OR mantık devreleri örneği.
        3.3.11 Zener diodes
            d30311a.asc: Çoklu çiftüşeklerle çıktı gerilimini sabit bir değerde düzenleme örneği.
            d30311b.asc: Ters kutuplu zener çiftüşekle çıktı gerilimi düzenlenmesi örneği.
            d30311c.asc: Kararlı zener çıktısında güç sarfiyatını düşük akımla azaltma örneği.
            d30311d.asc: Zener sabit geriliminin bağlı yükü beslemesi örneği.
            d30311e.asc: Düşük akımda yükün etkisiyle zenerin terskutba ulaşaması örneği.
            d30311f.asc: Zenerin terskutup regüleli kırılmasını sağlayacak enaz yükdirenç değeri örneği.
            d30311g.asc: Sırt-sırta 2 zenerle sinüs dalgasının kırpılması örneği.
        3.3.12 Special-purpose diodes
            d303123a.asc: LED ışık saçan çiftüşek devresindeki akım ayarı örneği.
            d303123b.asc: LED ile daha yüksek dc gerilim için akım düşürücü direnç hesabı örneği.
            d303123c.asc: Çoklu serili paralel LED çiftüşekli devre örneği.
            d303123d.asc: AC kaynakla LED terskutbu önleyen zıt bağlantı örneği.
        3.3.13 Other diode technologies
        3.3.14 SPICE models
            d30314a.asc: Aynı devredeki üç farklı koşut çiftüşeğin akım-gerilim grafiği örneği.
            d30314b.asc: Normal diyotu zener olarak modelleme örneği.
            d30314c.asc: İki zıt diyotu terste kenetli zener olarak işlevlendirme örneği.
    3.4. Bipolar Junction Transistors
        3.4.1 Introduction
        3.4.2 The transistor as a switch
            d30402a.asc: Bir NPN transistörü lamba düğmesi olarak kullanma örneği.
            d30402b.asc: Bir NPN transistörü CSW'li lamba düğmesi olarak kullanma örneği.
        3.4.3 Meter check of a transistor
            d30403.asc: Kontrolle npn ve pnp transistörleri saptama örneği.
        3.4.4 Active mode operation
            d30404a.asc: BJT transistörün kesikle doygunluk arası eğimi örneği.
            d30404b.asc: BJT için akım ve gerilim kaynaklarının birlikte süpürmesi örneği.
        3.4.5 The common-emitter amplifier
            d30405a.asc: Ortak yayıcı yükselteç örneği.
            d30405b.asc: AC sinyal girişli ortak yayıcı yükselteç örneği.
            d30405c.asc: AC sinyal girişli ortak yayıcı PNP yükselteç örneği.
        3.4.6 The common-collector amplifier
            d30406a.asc: Ortak toplayıcı yükselteç örneği.
            d30406b.asc: AC girdi sinyalli tersimesiz ortak toplayıcı yükselteç örneği.
            d30406c.asc: Darlington  tersimesiz ortak toplayıcı yükselteç örneği.
        3.4.7 The common-base amplifier
            d30407a.asc: Ortak temel DC gerilim yükselteç devresi örneği.
            d30407b.asc: Ortak temel AC gerilim yükselteç devresi örneği.
            d30407c.asc: Ortak temel pnp AC gerilim yükselteç devresi örneği.
            d30407d.asc: Azami kırpılmasız yük gerilim kazancının tespiti örneği.
            d30407e.asc: Dirençsiz ve dirençli ortak yayıcı-toplayıcı ve temel yükselteçler örneği.
        3.4.8 The cascode amplifier
            d30408a.asc: Seri bağlı ortak yayıcılı ve ortak temelli kaskod yükselteç örneği.
            d30408b.asc: Ortak yayıcılı yükselteç örneği.
            d30408c.asc: Kaskod ve ortak yayıcı yükselteç devreleri birlikte örneği.
        3.4.9 Biasing techniques
            d30409a.asc: A ve B sınıfı AC sinyal girişli ortak yayıcı yükselteç örneği.
            d30409b.asc: Değişen Ib ve Vce ile Ic-Vce grafikleri örneği.
            d30409c.asc: B sınıfı Q için pratik olmayan Vkaldıraç yerine toplayıcı gerilim bölücü kullanma örneği.
        3.4.10 Biasing calculations
            d304101.asc: Temel tetikleme devresi örneği.
            d304102.asc: Toplayıcı geribesleme tetikleme devresi örneği.
            d304103a.asc: Yayıcı tetikleme devresi örneği.
            d304103b.asc: Yayıcı tetikleyicide yayıcı dirence baypas sığaç örneği.
            d304104a.asc: Gerilim bölücü tetiklemeli yükselteç devresi örneği.
            d304104b.asc: Çift temel tetikleyicili kaskod yükselteç devresi örneği.
            d304104c.asc: Tüm tetikleyici devrelerin ve formüllerinin özeti örneği.
        3.4.11 Input and output coupling
            d30411a.asc: Direk bağlamalı kaynak ve çıktı sinyalleri örneği.
            d30411a.asc: Sığaçla bağlamalı kaynak ve çıktı sinyalleri örneği.
            d30411c.asc: Ortak yayıcılı sığaçla kaynak-çıktı bağlamalı 3 etap yükselteçli devre örneği.
            d30411a.asc: Direk kaynak bağlamalı ve dönüştüreç çıktılı yükselteç örneği.
            d30411e.asc: Sığaçla kaynak ve yük bağlamalı 3 etap dönüştüreçli yükselteç örneği.
            d30411f.asc: Dönüştüreçle birleştirilen pozitif-negatif yükselteç örneği.
            d30411g.asc: Dönüştüreç yerine yükselteç telafili direk bağlantılı pozitif-negatif devre örneği.
        3.4.12 Feedback
            d30412a.asc: Ortak yayıcı sığaçla kaynak birleştirici gerilim bölücü tetiklemeli yükselteç örneği.
            d30412b.asc: Sığaç birleşimli ortak yayıcı negatif toplayıcı geribeslemeli yükselteç örneği.
            d30412c.asc: Sığaç birleşimli ortak yayıcı negatif yayıcı geribeslemeli yükselteç örneği.
            d30412d.asc: Sığaç birleşimli ortak toplayıcı yükselteç örneği.
            d30412e.asc: Sığaç birleşimli ortak yayıcı negatif yayıcı sığaç-baypas geribeslemeli yükselteç örneği.
            d30412f.asc: Direk bağlamalı üç basamaklı geribeslemesiz ve beslemeli yükselteç örneği.
        3.4.13 Amplifier impedances
            d30413.asc: Yükselteçlerin gerilim-akım kazançları ve girdi-çıktı engeleçleri örneği.
        3.4.14 Current mirrors
            d30414.asc: Akım aynası yükselteç devreleri örneği.
        3.4.15 Transistor ratings and packages
        3.4.16 BJT quirks
            d304161.asc: Ortak yayıcı yükseltecin çıktı sinyalinde bozulma örneği.
            d304166.asc: Paralel ortak yayıcılarda ısınma çığını önleyen yayıcı balast/ağırlık direnci örneği.
    3.5. Junction Field-Effect Transistors
        3.5.1 Introduction
        3.5.2 The transistor as a switch
            d30502.asc: Normal bir aç-kapa düğmesi olarak kullanılan JFET örneği.
        3.5.3 Meter check of a transistor
        3.5.4 Active-mode operation
            d30504.asc: Kavşak yükseltecin aktif kipte Vcc ve Vin için DC süpürme grafikleri örneği.
        3.5.5 The common-source amplifier – PENDING
        3.5.6 The common-drain amplifier – PENDING
        3.5.7 The common-gate amplifier – PENDING
        3.5.8 Biasing techniques – PENDING
        3.5.9 Transistor ratings and packages – PENDING
        3.5.10 JFET quirks – PENDING
    3.6. Insulated-Gate Field-Effect Transistors
        3.6.1 Introduction
        3.6.2 Depletion-type IGFETs
            d30602.asc: IGFET yükseltecin çeşitli kapı-tetiklemeli süpürme karakteristikleri örneği.
        3.6.3 Enhancement-type IGFETs – PENDING
        3.6.4 Active-mode operation – PENDING
        3.6.5 The common-source amplifier – PENDING
        3.6.6 The common-drain amplifier – PENDING
        3.6.7 The common-gate amplifier – PENDING
        3.6.8 Biasing techniques – PENDING
        3.6.9 Transistor ratings and packages – PENDING
        3.6.10 IGFET quirks – PENDING
        3.6.11 MESFETs – PENDING
        3.6.12 IGBTs
            d30612.asc: Yüksek akım düğmesi olarak yükselteçlerin kullanılması örneği.
    3.7. Thyristors
        3.7.1 Hysteresis
        3.7.2 Gas discharge tubes
        3.7.3 The Shockley Diode
            d30703a.asc: Shockley diyodunun histeri eğrisi örneği.
            d30703b.asc: Shockley çiftüşeğin özel .asy sembollü devresi örneği.
            d30703bx.asc: İki npn-pnp yükselteçten tasarımlanan şokli çiftüşeği alt-örneği.
            d30703bx.asy: Şokli çiftüşek tasarımın çizim sembolü alt-örneği.
        3.7.4 The DIAC
            d30704a.asc: Sinüs AC kaynağının heriki yönünde de tetiklenen DIAC çift Şotki açık örneği.
            d30704b.asc: Sinüs AC kaynağının heriki yönünde de tetiklenen DIAC çift Şokli sembollü örneği.
            d30704c.asc: Sinüs AC kaynağının heriki yönünde de tetiklenen özel sembollü Diyak örneği.
            d30704cx.asc: Çift şokli tasarımlı Diyak alt-örneği.
            d30704cx.asy: Çift şokli tasarımlı Diyak çizim sembollü alt-örneği.
        3.7.5 The Silicon-Controlled Rectifier (SCR)
            d30705a.asc: Sinüs AC kaynağının heriki yönünde de tetiklenen çift npn-pnp yükselteçli üç-bağlantılı tristör(SCR/SemiconductorRectifier) örneği.
            d30705b.asc: Sinüs AC kaynağının pozitif dalgasında tetiklenen tasarım SCR örneği.
            d30705bx.asc: İki npn-pnp yükselteç ve 3 çıkışlı SCR tasarımı alt-örneği.
            d30705bx.asy: 3 çıkışlı SCR çizim sembolü alt-örneği.
            d30705c.asc: Ayrı kapı darbesi yerine aynı devrenin sığaçlı geciktirme tetiklemesi örneği.
        3.7.6 The TRIAC
            d30706a.asc: Triyak bileşeniyle ev lambalarında çift yönlü AC gerilim kırpıntısı örneği.
            d30706ax.asc: İki SCR bağlantılı Triyak tasarımı alt-örneği.
            d30706ax.asy: 3 çıkışlı Triyak çizim sembolü alt-örneği.
            d30706b.asc: Diyaklı triyak tetiklemesiyle ev lambalarında %50 tasarruf kırpıntısı örneği.
            d30706c.asc: Triyak bileşeniyle ev lambalarında çift yönlü AC gerilim kırpıntısı örneği.
        3.7.7 Optothyristors
        3.7.8 The Unijunction Transistor (UJT)
            d30708.asc: NJFET osilasyon devresinden tristör tetikleyici yapma örneği.
        3.7.9 The Silicon-Controlled Switch (SCS)
            d30709.asc: SCS/SiliconControlledSwitch devresinin pnp-npn yükselteçlerden bilişimi örneği.
        3.7.10 Field-effect-controlled thyristors
            d30710.asc: MCT/MosfetControlledSwitch ile devreyi pozitif darbeyle açma ve negatifle kapama işlevi örneği.
    3.8. Operational Amplfiers
        3.8.1 Introduction
            d30801a.asc: Tek girişli opamp/işyük yükselteç devresi örneği.
            d30801b.asc: Çift girişli İşYük evrensel (mamematik) işlemsel yükselteç devresi örneği.
        3.8.2 Single-ended and differential amplifiers
        3.8.3 The ”operational” amplifier
            d30803a.asc: Karşılaştırıcı olarak kullanılan gerilimbölerli İşYük devresi örneği.
            d30803b.asc: Gerilimbölerle karşılaştırıcı İşYük'ün sinüs'ten kare dalga üretmesi örneği.
            d30803c.asc: Seri İşYük'lerle çubukgrafik sürücü devresi örneği.
        3.8.4 Negative feedback
            d30804.asc: Geri beslemeli İşYük devresinde stabilite dengesi örneği.
        3.8.5 Divided feedback
            d30805a.asc: Bölünerek geri beslemeli İşYük devresi örneği.
            d30805b.asc: Bölünerek geri beslemeli İşYük devresinde heriki girdiyi sıfırlama örneği.
        3.8.6 An analogy for divided feedback
            d30806.asc: Pozitif veya negatif tersinir ve tersinmez girdili İşYük devreleri örneği.
        3.8.7 Voltage-to-current signal conversion
            d30807.asc: Gerilim'den akım'a sinyal çevrimli İşYük devresi örneği.
        3.8.8 Averager and summer circuits
            d30808.asc: Ortalayıcıdan İşYük toplayıcı tersinmez ve tersinir devreleri örneği.
        3.8.9 Building a differential amplifier
            d30809.asc: Gerilim girdileri farkını veren yüksek engeleç tamponlu İşYük devresi örneği.
        3.8.10 The instrumentation amplifier
            d3810.asc: Aygıtsal İşYük devresinde kazancın dirençle sağlanması örneği.
        3.8.11 Differentiator and integrator circuits
            d30811.asc: Türevci ve tümleyici İşYük devreleri örneği.
        3.8.12 Positive feedback
            d30812.asc: Pozitif geribelemeli İşYük devresi örneği.
            d3081231.asc: Aygıtsal İşYük devresinde ortak-kısadevre girdi kazancı örneği.
            d3081232.asc: Tersinir geribeslemeli İşYük'de girdi sinyal tel direncinin telafisi örneği.
        3.8.13 Practical considerations
            d308136.asc: Tersinmez İşYük devresinde giriş-çıkış fazlarında kayma örneği.
        3.8.14 Operational amplifier models
            d30814.asc: Ayrık yükselteçlerden yarattığımız basit İşYük entegresinin testi örneği.
            d30814x.asc: 2 pnp ve 4 npn'li ayrık yükselteçlerden tasarımladığımız basit İşYük entegresi alt-örneği.
            d30814x.asy: Basit İşYük entegresi çizim sembolü alt-örneği.
        3.8.15 Data
    3.9. Practical Analog Semiconductor Circuits
        3.9.1 ElectroStatic Discharge
        3.9.2 Power supply circuits – INCOMPLETE
        3.9.3 Amplifier circuits – PENDING
            d30903.asc: 3 wat'lık ses yükselteç devresi örneği.
        3.9.4 Oscillator circuits – INCOMPLETE
            d30904.asc: Faz kayması düzeltilmiş salınım yükselteç devresi örneği.
        3.9.5 Phase-locked loops – PENDING
        3.9.6 Radio circuits – INCOMPLETE
            d30906a.asc: Çiftüşek veya yükselteç ayraçlı RF kristal radyo alıcı devreleri örneği.
            d30906b.asc: İlk kütlesel üretim yükselteçli radyo devresi örneği.
            d30906c.asc: Küçük sinyalle çok yüksek kazanç veren kaskod yükselteç örneği.
        3.9.7 Computational circuits
            d30907a.asc: İkili/digital ve şekilli/analog devrelerle 25 sayısının temsili örneği.
            d30907b.asc: İşYük devrelerle analog aritmetik işlemler örneği.
        3.9.8 Measurement circuits – INCOMPLETE
        3.9.9 Control circuits – PENDING
    3.10. Active Filters
    3.11. DC Motor Drives
        3.11.1 Pulse Width Modulation
            d31101.asc: PWM/PulseWidtModulation ve karşılaştırıcı İşYük ile DC motor kontrol sinyali üretme örneği.
    3.12. Inverters and AC Motor Drives
    3.13. Electron Tubes
        3.13.1 Introduction
        3.13.2 Early tube history
        3.13.3 The triode
        3.13.4 The tetrode
        3.13.5 Beam power tubes
        3.13.6 The pentode
        3.13.7 Combination tubes
        3.13.8 Tube parameters
        3.13.9 Ionization (gas-filled) tubes
        3.13.10 Display tubes - CRT
        3.13.11 Microwave tubes
        3.13.12 Tubes versus Semiconductors

4. Digital (67 adet)
    4.1. Numeration Systems
    4.2. Binary Arithmetic
    4.3. Logic Gates
        4.3.1. Digital signals and gates
            d40301.asc: BJT-NPN yükselteçle NOT/değil mantıksal kapı devresi örneği.
        4.3.2. The NOT gate
            d40302.asc: Tam bir kesinti/doygunluk güvenceli NOT kapı devresi örneği.
        4.3.3. The "buffer" gate
            d40303.asc: Tampon/buffer mantık kapı devresiyle girdiyi çıktıya yansıtma örneği.
        4.3.4. Multiple-input gates
            4.3.4.1. The AND gate
                d403041.asc: Çoklu girdi ihtimalli AND/VE kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.4.2. The NAND gate
                d403042.asc: Çoklu girdili NAND (NOT AND) kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.4.3. The OR gate
                d403043.asc: Çoklu girdili OR/VEYA kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.4.4. The NOR gate
                d403044.asc: NOR (NOT OR) çoklu girdili kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.4.5. The Negative-AND gate
                d403045.asc: Çoklu girdili negatif AND mantıksal kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.4.6. The Negative-OR gate
                d403046.asc: Çoklu girdili negatif OR mantıksal kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.4.7. The Exclusive-OR gate
                d403047.asc: İstisna OR/XOR kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.4.8. The Exclusive-NOR gate
                d403048.asc: Çoklu girdili istisna NOR/XNOR mantıksal kapı devresi örneği.
        4.3.5. TTL NAND and AND gates
            d40305.asc: Çift girdili NAND ve AND devresi benzeri örneği.
        4.3.6. TTL NOR and OR gates
            d40306.asc: Çift girdili NOR ve OR kapı devreleri örneği.
        4.3.7. CMOS gate circuitry
            d40307.asc: CMOS kapı devresi örneği.
        4.3.8. Special-output gates
        4.3.9. Gate universitality
            4.3.9.1. Constructing the NOT function
                d403091.asc: Evrensel NAND ve NOR kapıdan NOT devresi örneği.
            4.3.9.2. Constructing the "buffer" function
                d403092.asc: Evrensel NAND ve NOR kapıdan Tampon devresi örneği.
            4.3.9.3. Constructing the AND function
                d403093.asc: Evrensel NAND ve NOR kapıdan AND kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.9.4. Constructing the NAND function
                d403094.asc: Evrensel NOR kapıdan NAND kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.9.5. Constructing the OR function
                d403095.asc: Evrensel NAND ve NOR kapıdan OR kapı devresi örneği.
            4.3.9.6. Constructing the NOR function
                d403096.asc: Evrensel NAND kapıdan NOR kapı devresi örneği.
        4.3.10. Logic signal voltage levels
        4.3.11. DIP gate packaging
    4.4. Switches
        4.4.1. Switch types
        4.4.2. Switch contact design
        4.4.3. Contact "normal" state and make/break sequence
        4.4.4. Contact "bounce"
    4.5. Electromagnetic Relays
        4.5.1. Relay construction
        4.5.2. Contactors
        4.5.3. Time-delay relays
        4.5.4. Protective relays
        4.5.5. Solid-state relays
    4.6. Ladder Logic
        4.6.1. "Ladder" diagrams
        4.6.2. Digital logic functions
            d40602.asc: Merdiven basamağı düğmeli ikili mantık fonksiyonları örneği.
        4.6.3. Permissive and interlock circuits
        4.6.4. Motor control circuits
        4.6.5. Fail-safe design
        4.6.6. Programmable logic controllers
    4.7. Boolean Algebra
        4.7.1. Introduction
        4.7.2. Boolean arithmetic
            d40702.asc: Bool aritmetiğinin mantık devreleri örneği.
        4.7.3. Boolean lgebraic identities
            d40703.asc: Bool cebirsel özdeşlikler ve mantık devreleri örneği.
        4.7.4. Boolean algebraic properties
            d40704.asc: Bool cebirsel özelliklerin devreleştirilmesi örneği.
        4.7.5. Boolean rules for simplification
            d40705.asc: Bool sadeleştirme kurallarını devreleştirme örneği.
        4.7.6. Circuit simplification examples
            d40706.asc: Karmaşık kapı ve merdiven devrelerini sadeleştirme örneği.
        4.7.7. The Exclusive-OR function
            d40707.asc: XOR kapısının açılım devresi örneği.
        4.7.8. DeMorgan's Theorems
            d40708.asc: DeMorgan teoremleriyle tümlenen grubu sadeleştirme örneği.
        4.7.9. Converting truth tables into Boolean expressions
            d40709.asc: Gerçeklik tablosundan Bool mantık kapıları ve merdiven basamağı devresi örneği.
    4.8. Karnaugh Mapping
        4.8.1. Introduction
        4.8.2. Venn diagrams and sets
        4.8.3. Boolean Relationships on Venn Diagrams
        4.8.4. Making a Venn diagram look like a Karnaugh map
        4.8.5. Karnaugh maps, truth tables, and Boolean expressions
            d40805.asc: Mantık kapıları verili Bool ifadesi ve Karnaugh haritalarıyla sadeleştirme örneği.
        4.8.6. Logic simplification with Karnaugh maps
            d40806.asc: Karnaugh haritalarla mantıksal sadeleştirmeler örneği.
        4.8.7. Larger 4-variable Karnaugh maps
            d40807.asc: 4'ten fazla değişkenli Karnaugh haritalarını sadeleştirme örneği.
        4.8.8. Minterm vs maxterm solution
            d40808.asc: Karnaugh haritada birliterim yada sıfırlıterim yöntemli sadeleştirme örneği.
        4.8.9. Σ (sum) and Π (product) notation
            d40809.asc: Σm birliterim çarpımlarının  toplamları ve ΠM sıfırlıterim toplamlarının çarpımları örneği.
        4.8.10. Don't care cells in the Karnaugh map
            d40810.asc: Karnaugh haritalamada aldırma (sıfır/bir farketmez) terimleri örneği.
        4.8.11. Larger 5&6-variable Karnaugh maps
            d40811.asc: Daha büyük 5-6 değişkenli Karnaugh haritaları örneği.
    4.9. Combinational Logic Functions
        4.9.1 Introduction
        4.9.2 A Half-Adder
            d40902.asc: Yarım toplayıcı birleşimsel mantık fonksiyonlu devre örneği.
        4.9.3 A Full-Adder
            d40903.asc: Tam toplayıcı birleşimsel mantık fonksiyonlu devre örneği.
        4.9.4 Decoder
            d40904.asc: Girdiyi 2^n çıktıya çeviren dekoder kod çözücü devresi örneği.
        4.9.5 Encoder
            d40905.asc: 4 girdi değişkenden 7 farklı çıktı üreten kodlayıcı devresi örneği.
        4.9.6 Demultiplexers
            d40906.asc: Tek girdiden çoklu çıkış türeten demultiplexer/çoklayıcı devresi örneği.
        4.9.7 Multiplexers
            d40907.asc: Çoklu girdiden tek çıkış türeten multiplexer/tekleyici devresi örneği.
        4.9.8 Using multiple combinational circuits
    4.10. Multivibrators
        4.10.1 Digital logic with feedback
            d41001.asc: Geri beslemeli mantıksal kapı devreleri örneği.
        4.10.2 The S-R latch
            d41002.asc: Çift durumlu kur-tekrarkur mandallı çoklutitreşimci devresi örneği.
        4.10.3 The gated S-R latch
            d41003.asc: Kapılı K-T mandallı çoklutitreşimci devresi örneği.
        4.10.4 The D latch
            d41004.asc: D-mandallı çoklutitreşimci devresi örneği.
        4.10.5 Edge-triggered latches: Flip-Flops
            d41005.asc: Kenar-tetiklemeli flip-flop/çiftdurumlu mandal devresi örneği.
        4.10.6 The J-K flip-flop
            d41006.asc: Pozitif-kenar tetiklemeli J-K flip-flop çoklutitreşim devresi örneği.
        4.10.7 Asynchronous flip-flop inputs
        4.10.8 Monostable multivibrators
    4.11. Sequential Circuits
        4.11.1 Binary count sequence
            d41101.asc: İkili sayı dizilim J-K flip-flop devresi örneği.
            d41101a.asc: PulseMaker/DarbeYapıcı saat döngüsel karedalga devre şeması alt-örneği.
            d41101a.asy: PulseMaker/DarbeYapıcı sembolü alt-örneği.
            d41101b.asc: Yükselen kenar saatli J-KFlip-Flop/JKÇiftDurum devre şeması alt-örneği.
            d41101b.asy: Yükselen kenar saatli J-KFlip-Flop/JKÇiftDurum sembolü alt-örneği.
        4.11.2 Asynchronous counters
            d41102.asc: Asenkron sayaçlarla 4-bitli JKFlip-Flop devresi örneği.
        4.11.3 Synchronous counters
            d41103.asc: Senkron sayaçlarla 4-bitli JKFlip-Flop devresi örneği.
        4.11.4 Counter modulus
            d41105.asc: D ve JK ÇiftDurum sıralı devresiyle sonlu durum makinesi yaratma örneği.
        4.11.5 Finite State Machines
            d41105a.asc: Saatli ve Kur/Sıfırla girişli JKÇiftDurum devresi örneği.
    4.12. Shift Registers
        4.12.1 Introduction
        4.12.2 Serial-in/serial-out shift register
            d41202.asc: Seri girip seri çıkan kayan yazmaç devresi örneği.
        4.12.2.1 Serial-in/serial-out devices
        4.12.3 Parallel-in, serial-out shift register
            4.12.3.1 Parallel-in/serial-out devices
                d41203.asc: DFF ile paralel giriş seri çıkış kayan yazmaç devresi örneği.
            4.12.3.2 Practical applications
        4.12.4 Serial-in, parallel-out shift register
            4.12.4.1 Serial-in/ parallel-out devices
                d41204.asc: DFF ile 4'lü seri giriş paralel çıkış kayan yazmaç devresi örneği.
            4.12.4.2 Practical applications
        4.12.5 Parallel-in, parallel-out, universal shift register
            4.12.5.1 Parallel-in/ parallel-out and universal devices
                d41205.asc: DFF ile 3'lü paraleli giriş paralel çıkış kayan yazmaç devresi örneği.
            4.12.5.2 Practical applications
        4.12.6 Ring counters
            4.12.6.1 Johnson counters
                d41206. Geridönüşü negatif çıkıştan alan Johnson sayaçları örneği.
    4.13. Digital-Analog Conversion
        4.13.1 Introduction
        4.13.2 The R/2nR DAC
            d41302.asc: R/2^nR DAC/DigitalAnalogConverter/SayısaldanÖrnekseleÇevirici devresi örneği.
        4.13.3 The R/2R DAC
            d41303.asc: R/2R DAC/SayısaldanÖrnekseleÇevirici devresi örneği.
        4.13.4 Flash ADC
            d41304.asc: Çakar/flash ADC/AnalogDigitalConverter/ÖrnekseldenSayısalaÇevirici devre örneği.
        4.13.5 Digital ramp ADC
        4.13.6 Successive approximation ADC
        4.13.7 Tracking ADC
        4.13.8 Slope (integrating) ADC
            d41308.asc: Eğimli tümleyen ADC/ÖrnekseldenSayısalaÇevirici devre örneği.
        4.13.9 Delta-Sigma (∆Σ) ADC
            d41309.asc: ∆Σ/Σ∆ DeltaSigma ADC/ÖrnekseldenSayısalaÇevirici devresi örneği.
        4.13.10Practical considerations of ADC circuits
    4.14. Digital Communication
        4.14.1 Introduction
        4.14.2 Networks and busses
            4.14.2.1 Short-distance busses
            4.14.2.2 Extended-distance networks
        4.14.3 Data flow
        4.14.4 Electrical signal types
        4.14.5 Optical data communication
        4.14.6 Network topology
            4.14.6.1 Point-to-point
            4.14.6.2 Bus
            4.14.6.3 Star
            4.14.6.4 Ring
        4.14.7 Network protocols
        4.14.8 Practical considerations
    4.15. Digital Storage (Memory)
        4.15.1 Why digital?
        4.15.2 Digital memory terms and concepts
        4.15.3 Modern nonmechanical memory
        4.15.4 Historical, nonmechanical memory technologies
        4.15.5 Read-only memory
        4.15.6 Memory with moving parts: ”Drives”
    4.16. Principles of Digital Computing
        4.16.1 A binary adder
        4.16.2 Look-up tables
        4.16.3 Finite-state machines
        4.16.4 Microprocessors
        4.16.5 Microprocessor programming

5. Experiments (66 adet)
    5.1. Introduction
        5.1.1. Electronics As Science
        5.1.2. Setting Up A Home Lab
    5.2. Basic Concepts and Test Equipment
        5.2.1. Voltmeter usage
        5.2.2. Ohmmeter usage
        5.2.3 A very simple circuit
            d50203.asc: Deneysel kurulan ilk basit bataryalı ampül devresi örneği.
        5.2.4. Ammeter usage
        5.2.5. Ohm’s Law
        5.2.6. Nonlinear resistance
        5.2.7. Power dissipation
        5.2.8 Circuit with a switch
        5.2.9 Electromagnetism
        5.2.10. Electromagnetic induction
    5.3. DC Circuits
        5.3.1. Introduction
        5.3.2. Series batteries
            d50302.asc: Seri ve paralel bataryalarla güçlendirilmiş yüksek wat beslemeli devre örneği.
        5.3.3. Parallel batteries
        5.3.4. Voltage divider
            d50304.asc: 3 seri dirençli gerilim bölücü devre örneği.
        5.3.5. Current divider
            d50305.asc: Uygulamalı paralel dirençli akım bölücü devre örneği.
        5.3.6. Potentiometer as a voltage divider
            d50306.asc: Gerilim bölücü olarak ayarlanabilir potansiyometrik direnç devresi örneği.
        5.3.7. Potentiometer as a rheostat
            d50307.asc: Reosta olarak kullanılan pot dirençli motor dönü kontrol devresi örneği.
        5.3.8. Precision potentiometer
            d50308.asc: 3 pot ile hassas reostalı gerilim bölücü devresi örneği.
        5.3.9. Rheostat range limiting
            d50309.asc: Reostayla kapsam sınırlamalı gerilim gölücü devresi örneği.
        5.3.10. Thermoelectricity
        5.3.11. Make your own multimeter
        5.3.12. Sensitive voltage detector
        5.3.13. Potentiometric voltmeter
            d50313.asc: Gerilimlerin eşitlendiği sıfır akımlı pot'lu gerilimölçer devresi örneği.
        5.3.14. 4-wire resistance measurement
            d50314.asc: Akımölçer ve gerilimölçerle 4-telli makara iletken direncini hesaplama örneği.
        5.3.15. A very simple computer
            d50315.asc: Basit bir kompüter devresiyle gerilim ortalayıcı örneği.
        5.3.16. Potato battery
        5.3.17. Capacitor charging and discharging
            d50317.asc: Bir sığaçın şarj ve deşarj süreleri örneği.
        5.3.18. Rate-of-change indicator
            d50318.asc: Pot'lu sığaçla değişim oranı göstergesi örneği.
    5.4. AC Circuits
        5.4.1. Introduction
        5.4.2. Transformer - power supply
            d50402.asc: 220V/6V dönüştüreç güç kaynağı devresi örneği.
        5.4.3. Build a transformer
            d50403.asc: Elle sarım düşük gerilimli dönüştüreç yapımı örneği.
        5.4.4. Variable inductor
            d50404.asc: Değişken reaktans/tepkileçli irkileç bobini örneği.
        5.4.5. Sensitive audio detector
            d50405.asc: Ayarlı pot, paralel çiftüşek ve dönüştüreçli duyarlı ses algılayıcı devresi örneği.
        5.4.6. Sensing AC magnetic fields
        5.4.7. Sensing AC electric fields
        5.4.8. Automotive alternator
        5.4.9. Induction motor
        5.4.10. Induction motor, large
        5.4.11. Phase shift
            d50411.asc: Seri direnç ve sığaç devreli faz kayması örneği.
        5.4.12. Sound cancellation
        5.4.13. Musical keyboard as a signal generator
            d50413.asc: Sinyal üreteci olarak elektronik müzik klavyesi kulaklık girişinin kullanılması örneği.
        5.4.14. PC Oscilloscope
        5.4.15. Waveform analysis
            d50415.asc: Dalgabiçimi analizi için zaman ve frekans süpürmesi örneği.
        5.4.16. Inductor-capacitor ”tank” circuit
            d50416.asc: Paralel irkileç ve sığaçlı sinüs osilasyonlu tank devresi örneği.
        5.4.17. Signal coupling
    5.5. Discrete Semiconductor Circuit
        5.5.1. Introduction
        5.5.2 Commutating diode
            d50502.asc: İrkileç geritepmesini hafifleten çiftüşek devresi örneği.
        5.5.3. Half-wave rectifier
            d50503.asc: 6V-RMS AC gerilim kaynak ve çiftüşekli DC motor yarım dalga doğrultaç devresi örneği.
        5.5.4. Full-wave center-tap rectifier
            d50504.asc: Merkezi topraklı çift dönüştüreç çıkışlı ve iki çiftüşekli tamdalga düzelteç devre örneği.
        5.5.5. Full-wave bridge rectifier
            d50505.asc: 220V/8.485V dönüştürece köprü düzelteçli AC/DC çevrim devresi örneği.
        5.5.6. Rectifier/filter circuit
            d50506.asc: 220V/8.485V dönüştürece köprü düzelteç ve sığaç filtreli AC/DC çevrim devresi örneği.
        5.5.7. Voltage regulator
            d50507.asc: Ters zener çiftüşekle gerilim regülatörü/düzelteç devresi örneği.
        5.5.8. Transistor as a switch
            d50508.asc: Düğme olarak bir yükseltecin kullanılması örneği.
        5.5.9. Static electricity sensor
            d50509.asc: LED lambası için bir JFET yükselteç düğmesini kullanma örneği.
        5.5.10. Pulsed-light sensor
        5.5.11. Voltage follower
            d50511.asc: BJT yükseltecin gerilim takipçi olarak kullanılması örneği.
        5.5.12. Common-emitter amplifier
            d50512.asc: Ortak gönderici yükselteçle çeşitli denemeler örneği.
        5.5.13. Multi-stage amplifier
            d50513.asc: Üç katmanlı ve geribeslemeli tersinir yükselteçler devresi örneği.
        5.5.14. Current mirror
            d50514.asc: Karşılıklı iki NPN yükselteçle akım aynası devresi örneği.
        5.5.15. JFET current regulator
            d50515.asc: JFET akım regülatörü örneği.
        5.5.16. Differential amplifier
            d50516.asc: Karşılaştırıcı-benzeri 2 npn'li  fark yükselteç devresi örneği.
        5.5.17. Simple op-amp
            d50517.asc: 4 NPN ve 2 PNP yükselteçleriyle bir OpAmp/İşYük entegresi örneği.
        5.5.18. Audio oscillator
            d50518.asc: Sessel salınım üreten yükselteç örneği.
        5.5.19. Vacuum tube audio amplifier
    5.6. Analog Integrated Circuits
        5.6.1. Introduction
        5.6.2. Voltage comparator
            d50602.asc: Gerilim karşılaştırıcı İşYük devresi örneği.
        5.6.3. Precision voltage follower
            d50603. Hassas gerilim takipçi İşYük devresi örneği.
        5.6.4. Noninverting amplifier
            d50604.asc: Girdisi ve geribeslemesi pot ayarlı İşYük devresi örneği.
        5.6.5. High-impedance voltmeter
            d50606.asc: Yüksek İşYük engeleçli gerilimölçer devresi örneği.
        5.6.6. Integrator
            d50606.asc: Sabit DC girdiyle değişken zamanlı sığaç birikimli tümleyici İşYük devresi örneği.
        5.6.7. 555 audio oscillator
            d50607a.asc: NE555 astabil entegresiyle karedalga salınımı üretme örneği.
            d50607.asc: NE555 zamanlayıcı IC/IntegratedCircuit/TümleşikDevre ile ses gerilim sinyal salınımı örneği.
        5.6.8. 555 ramp generator
            d50608.asc: NE555 TD/TümleşikDevre ile düz-rampa dalga üreteci örneği.
        5.6.9. PWM power controller
            d50609.asc: NE555 ve çift İşYük'le PWM değişken karedalgalı yük gücü kontrolu örneği.
        5.6.10. Class B audio amplifier
            d50610.asc: B sınıfı ses sinyali yükselteç devresi örneği.
    5.7. Digital Integrated Circuits
        5.7.1. Introduction
        5.7.2. Basic gate function
            d50702. Temel AND/NAND kapı devresi örneği.
        5.7.3. NOR gate S-R latch
            d50703.asc: OR/NOR kapısının çapraz geribeslemeli çoklutitreşim devresi örneği.
        5.7.4. NAND gate S-R enabled latch
            d50704.asc: NAND kapısı S-R-E/Set-Reset-Enable/Kur-Sıfırla-Etkinleştir mandallama devresi örneği.
        5.7.5. NAND gate S-R flip-flop
            d50705.asc: NAND kapılı SRFlipFlop/KSÇiftDurum devresi örneği.
            d50705a.asc: Yükselen saat tetiklemeli S-RÇiftDurum devre şeması alt-örneği.
            d50705a.asy: Yükselen saat tetiklemeli S-RÇiftDurum devre sembolü alt-örneği.
            d50705b.asc: Yükselen tetiklemeli darbe yapıcı saat karedalga sinyal üretici şeması alt-örneği.
            d50705b.asy: Yükselen tetiklemeli darbe yapıcı saat karedalga sinyal üretici sembolü alt-örneği.
        5.7.6. LED sequencer
            d50706.asc: Darbe üretici 555 zamanlayıcı entegresi ve LED devresi örneği.
        5.7.7. Simple combination lock
            d50707.asc: Basit kombine kilit düğmeli mantıksal kapılı LED devresi örneği.
        5.7.8. 3-bit binary counter
            d50708.asc: 3 bitli LED lambalı sayaç devresi örneği.
            d50708a.asc: Saatli Set-Reset JKÇiftDurum devresi alt-örneği.
        5.7.9. 7-segment display
    5.8. NE555 Timer Circuits
        5.8.1. The 555 IC
        5.8.2. NE555 schmitt trigger
            d50802.asc: NE555 zamanlayıcının Schmitt tetikleyici olarak kullanılması örneği.
        5.8.3. NE555 hysteretic oscilator
            d50803.asc: NE555 isterik osilatör devresi örneği.
        5.8.4. NE555 monostable Multivibrator
            d50804.asc: NE555 tikel stabil çoklu salınım devresi örneği.
        5.8.5. CMOS NE555 long duration mimimum parts red LED flasher
            d50805.asc: NE555 dayanıklı enaz pil sarfiyatlı kızıl LED ışıldaklı devre örneği.
        5.8.6. CMOS NE555 long duration blue LED flasher
            d50806.asc: NE555 asgari sarfiyatlı mavi LED flaşör devresi örneği.
        5.8.7. CMOS NE555 long duration flyback LED flasher
            d50807.asc: NE555 uzun ömürlü irkileçle gerilim yülselten çift LED flaşör devresi.
        5.8.8. How to make an inductor
        5.8.9. CMOS NE555 long duration red LED flasher
            d50809.asc: NE555 dayanıklı kızıl tek LED flaşör devresi örneği.

6. Reference
    6.1. Useful Equations and Conversion Factors
    6.2. Color Codes
    6.3. Conductor and Insulator Tables
    6.4. Algebra Reference
    6.5. Trigonometric Reference
    6.6. Calculus Reference
    6.7. Using The Spice Circuit Simulation Program
    6.8. Troubleshooting - Theory and Practice
    6.9. Circuit Schematic Sysbols
    6.10. Peridic Table of Elements

7. Practical Guide to Radio Frequency - RF Analysis and Design
    7.1. Introduction to RF Principles and Component
    7.2. Electromagnetic Spectrum
    7.3. Real-Life RF Signals
    7.4. RF Modulation
    7.5. RF Demodulation
    7.6. Selected Topics